<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<borneoResort>
	<borneoResort_title1>- Sutera Harbour Beach Resort and Marina Club -</borneoResort_title1>
	<borneoResort_img1>~/images/marina1.jpg</borneoResort_img1>
    <borneoResort_p1>Nestled between the shores of the South China Sea, fronting the tropical islands and the majestic Mount Kinabalu, is the grand expanse of Sutera Harbour Resort. The 384-acre resort provides a spectacular array of activities from its luxurious five-star hotels, championship golf course, marina and recreational facilities. The elegant business setting of The Pacific Sutera Hotel is complemented by the resort ambience of The Magellan Sutera Resort, offering a total of 956 guest rooms and suites of luxurious</borneoResort_p1>
	<borneoResort_title2>- The Pacific Sutera Resort -</borneoResort_title2>
    <borneoResort_img2>~/images/pacific-sutera-kota-kinabalu.jpg</borneoResort_img2>
	<borneoResort_p2>The luxurious 5-star The Pacific Sutera Hotel features 500 immaculately appointed rooms and suites with contemporary décor and dramatic views of either the sprawling golf course or of the sea and nearby tropical islands.</borneoResort_p2>
   <borneoResort_img3>~/images/sutera@.jpg</borneoResort_img3>
	<borneoResort_p3>The grand entrance and high-ceiling lobby lounge offer an uninterrupted, panoramic view of the ocean and is a popular meeting point for leisure and business travellers. The Pacific Club guests enjoy the magnificent views from the top floors where breakfast and cocktails are served in the exclusive Pacific Club Lounge.</borneoResort_p3>
	<borneoResort_title3>- The Magellan Sutera Resort -</borneoResort_title3>
    <borneoResort_img4>~/images/sutera-harbour-resort-pacific.jpg</borneoResort_img4>
	<borneoResort_p4>The Magellan Sutera Resort is a magnificent 5-star resort with 456 rooms and suites. The grand entrance is a majestic longhouse style lobby; an architectural tribute to the Rungus natives of Sabah. With fine timber furnishings and traditional handicraft artifacts, this resort is a favourite with families and couples and those seeking a relaxing, tropical holiday in Borneo. The suites are lavishly decorated and present fabulous views of beautifully manicured gardens or the South China Sea set against a backdrop of the islands of Tunku Abdul Rahman Marine Park.</borneoResort_p4>
	 <borneoResort_img5>~/images/SuteraHarbour.jpg</borneoResort_img5>
	<borneoResort_title4>- Nexus Karabunai beach Resort -</borneoResort_title4>
	<borneoResort_p5>Located just 28km from the city and 38km from Kota Kinabalu International Airport, Nexus Resort &amp; Spa Karambunai is set amidst 3,335 acres of natural and landscaped surroundings creating the perfect background for all 485 well-appointed guestrooms, suites and luxury villas. The award-winning 18-hole championship golf course and exclusive Borneo Spa complement the superb facilities of this magnificent resort which boasts eight restaurants and bars and an almost endless array of leisure and recreational activities.</borneoResort_p5>
	<borneoResort_img6>~/images/nexus.jpg</borneoResort_img6>
	<borneoResort_p6>Nexus Resort Karambunai lies on the west coast of Sabah, Malaysian Borneo, a destination that is accessible via direct or single-stop flights from the nations capital Kuala Lumpur and several major Asian cities such as Singapore, Bangkok, Sydney, Melbourne, Manila, Taipei, Hong Kong, Seoul, Tokyo, Guangzhou and Xiamen.</borneoResort_p6>
	<borneoResort_img7>~/images/nexus2.jpeg</borneoResort_img7>
	<borneoResort_hint1>Directions:</borneoResort_hint1>
	<borneoResort_p7>Situated on the spectacular Karambunai Peninsula, upon 3,335 acres of natural and landscaped surrounds, the resort is just 30 minutes from Kota Kinabalu city, the capital and gateway to Sabah, and only 40 minutes from Kota Kinabalu International Airport and Terminal 2 Kota Kinabalu. Transfers to the resort can easily be arranged by coach, private limousine or taxi.   Nexus Resort &amp; Spa Karambunai is accessible via direct or single-stop flights from the nation’s capital Kuala Lumpur and several major Asian cities such as Singapore, Bangkok, Sydney, Melbourne, Manila, Taipei, Hong Kong, Seoul, Tokyo, Guangzhou and Xiamen.</borneoResort_p7>
	<borneoResort_img8>~/images/karabunai.jpg</borneoResort_img8>
	<borneoResort_hint2>GPS Coordinates:</borneoResort_hint2>
	<borneoResort_hint3>N 6.114318 | E 116.108376,</borneoResort_hint3>
	<borneoResort_hint4>N 6. 6.85908, | E 116. 6.50256,</borneoResort_hint4>
	<borneoResort_hint5>N 6. 6, 51.544,, | E 116. 6, 30.153</borneoResort_hint5>
	<borneoResort_img9>~/images/nexus-karambunai-front.jpg</borneoResort_img9>
	<borneoResort_p8>The romanticism and mysticism of Borneo awaits you in the world’s last unexplored paradise. Nexus Resort &amp; Spa Karambunai lies on 3,335 acres of unrivalled natural and landscaped surroundings on the spectacular Karambunai Peninsula in Kota Kinabalu. The South China Sea, 6km of pristine white sandy beach and million-year old tropical rainforest poise as the majestic margin and backdrop.</borneoResort_p8>
	<borneoResort_title5>- Tanjung Aru Shangri La Kota Kinabalu Beach Resort -</borneoResort_title5>
	<borneoResort_p9>A gentle breeze caresses your face as you wake to the sound of waves lapping the beach. The balcony opens up to an inspiring vista of sparkling coral islands and swaying palm trees. This is the beginning of your vacation in our award-winning hotel in Kota Kinabalu.</borneoResort_p9>
	<borneoResort_img10>~/images/bembaran-beach-resort-arrival.jpg</borneoResort_img10>
	<borneoResort_p10>Located just 10 minutes away from the city, Shangri-La’s Tanjung Aru Resort and Spa, Kota Kinabalu, is a luxurious, tranquil retreat that provides the perfect setting for an amazing tropical getaway. Sophistication surrounds you in a lavishly decorated suite inspired by Borneo's rich cultural heritage.</borneoResort_p10>
	<borneoResort_img11>~/images/Nexus banana boat.jpg</borneoResort_img11>
	<borneoResort_p11>You wonder, "What to do in Kota Kinabalu?" Exciting adventures beckon as you set out to discover all Kota Kinabalu’s delights. Making your way to Kinabalu National Park,  you are thrust into a jungle paradise of natural wonders, rugged landscapes and scenic beauty.  From the Rafflesia, the largest flower in the world, to the famous orangutans in their natural habitat, breathtaking sights await you every step of the way.</borneoResort_p11>
	<borneoResort_img12>~/images/shangrila.jpg</borneoResort_img12>
	<borneoResort_p12>Departing from STAR Marina, the private jetty exclusively owned and operated by the resort, you head to the neighbouring coral islands, which are part of Tunku Abdul Rahman Marine Park. The clear blue waters surrounding the islands offer an amazing snorkeling experience with tropical fish and coral. Here, you can get your heart pumping with adrenaline by participating in water sports on the South China Sea. </borneoResort_p12>
	<borneoResort_img13>~/images/shangri-la-s-tanjung (1).jpg</borneoResort_img13>
	<borneoResort_p13>Back at the resort, you will find seven of the locals' favourite Kota Kinabalu restaurants and bars.  You look forward to a Sabah Golden Sunset Cocktail at Sunset Bar while soaking in the splendour of the famous Borneo sunset. Not long after, you wind down at Coco-Joe’s Bar &amp; Grill.  While lounging in one of the beach side cabanas and enjoying the sound of overlapping waves on the shores of Sunset Beach, you tuck into a delectable seafood tower. </borneoResort_p13>
	<borneoResort_img14>~/images/TANJUNG ARU.jpg</borneoResort_img14>
	<borneoResort_p14>A pampering session at CHI, The Spa rounds off the day. Renowned as one of the most picturesque spas in Kota Kinabalu, CHI, The Spa offers treatments based on traditional Asian healing philosophies.  You enjoy an enchanted and indulgent journey on the resort's private spa island. </borneoResort_p14>
	<borneoResort_img15>~/images/TAH-Your-Shangri-La-Story.jpg</borneoResort_img15>
	<borneoResort_p15>During every experience here, you are surrounded by natural beauty. Your dream vacation begins at Shangri-La’s Tanjung Aru Resort and Spa, Kota Kinabalu.</borneoResort_p15>
	
  
  
  
  </borneoResort>
