<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<borneoRainforest>
   <borneoRainforest_title1>Danum Valley</borneoRainforest_title1>
	<borneoRainforest_p1>130-million-year virgin Borneo rainforest, older than Amazon</borneoRainforest_p1>
	<borneoRainforest_img1>~/images/danum.gif</borneoRainforest_img1>
	<borneoRainforest_p2>Though a large part of Sabah is covered by forest, very few have seen the beauty of virgin Borneo rainforest. Most forest that we see around our cities and countryside is degraded jungle or secondary forest. Compared to regenerated forest, undisturbed virgin forest is characterised by taller trees, with denser, richer and more biodiversified of flora and fauna.</borneoRainforest_p2>
	<borneoRainforest_img2>~/images/Rfmap2.GIF</borneoRainforest_img2>
	<borneoRainforest_p3>Mostly lowland dipterocarp and riverine forest, Danum Valley is one of the richest conservation areas in the world with over 200 species of tree per hectare. You could find huge commercial timbers such as Kapur,Keruing, Seraya and Belian everywhere. To lumbering companies, these trees look like standing gold bars. To scientists, this forest is the least explored treasure, which holds the secrets that can change our future. But sadly, to most Sabahans, these are just wood that ought to be cut to give way to development.</borneoRainforest_p3>
	<borneoRainforest_title2>VALLEY TREKKING</borneoRainforest_title2>
	<borneoRainforest_title2_sub1>Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, </borneoRainforest_title2_sub1>
	<borneoRainforest_p4>The road has a lot of Proboscis and orangutan, and you would see many huge </borneoRainforest_p4>
	<borneoRainforest_p5>fed on the fruit tree in front of Borneo Rainforest Lodge (BRL).</borneoRainforest_p5>
	<borneoRainforest_img3>~/images/orang utan.jpeg</borneoRainforest_img3>
	<borneoRainforest_p6>According to the BRL staff, its name is Orang Utan and it always comes here during fruiting season. There is also another orangutan family also comes here quite often. Seeing orangutan in the wild is such a wonderful experience. King didn seem to bother about the presence of people and carried on his feeding from branch to branch.</borneoRainforest_p6>
	<borneoRainforest_title3>Danum Valley Rainforest Tours </borneoRainforest_title3>
	<borneoRainforest_title3_sub1> Duration: 3 days / 2 nights </borneoRainforest_title3_sub1>
	<borneoRainforest_p7>Trek in the Danum Valley, a conservation area well known for its rich diversity of flora and fauna. The Danum Valley Conservation Area covers more than 100,000 acres of virgin forest. It is widely considered to be one of the most important ecosystems in the world.</borneoRainforest_p7>
	<borneoRainforest_img4>~/images/zoo.jpg</borneoRainforest_img4>
	<borneoRainforest_p8>The scheduled transfer in the morning from Lahad Datu takes you over 97 km to the Danum Valley Conservation area where you will stay the night in the newly refurbished Borneo Rainforest Lodge. The activities on your first day include a visit to the Canopy Bridge and an introductory trail. Day 2 sees you trekking to View Point and Coffin Cliff in the day. In the evening you will be taken for a night walk. Danum Valley is home to many of Borneo's major wildlife attractions - the orang utan, Bornean gibbon, leaf monkeys, elephants, deer, wild boar, and even the rare rhinoceros including. Return to Lahad Datu after lunch on day 3 for your onward flight.</borneoRainforest_p8>
 </borneoRainforest>
