<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<waterRafting>
   <waterRafting_title1>White Water Rafting Tours</waterRafting_title1>
   <waterRafting_p1>Try whitewater rafting on the rivers of </waterRafting_p1>
	<waterRafting_p2>, which offer thrilling rides which will get your adrenaline pumping. Quite a change from the underwater world, you may be in for a bumpy ride! Kiulu has Grade I - II rapids and is an ideal choice for first time rafters and weak swimmers. Padas River is for the more experienced rafters with Grade III - IV rapids. Note: you must be able to swim and your active participation is required throughout the trips. </waterRafting_p2>
	<waterRafting_img1>~/images/Klias_River_Cruise_Boat.jpg</waterRafting_img1>
	<waterRafting_title2>Padas White Water Rafting</waterRafting_title2>
    <waterRafting_p3>Duration: 1 day trip </waterRafting_p3>
	<waterRafting_p4>Your trip starts from Kota Kinabalu at about 07:30 hrs on a 2½ hour overland journey to Tenom. In Tenom you will board the train to Rayoh where you start your white water rafting activity. Padas River is considered to be a Grade 4 white water river. This means you can expect medium-sized waves, rocks and drops. After heavy rain this can be quite an adrenalin ride! This also means that the briefing covers a wide range of rafting skills and techniques you will need to battle the rapids. </waterRafting_p4>
	<waterRafting_img2>~/images/raft.jpg</waterRafting_img2>
	<waterRafting_title3>Liwagu White Water Rafting</waterRafting_title3>
	<waterRafting_p5>Duration: 1 day trip </waterRafting_p5>
	<waterRafting_p6>The Liwagu River is located in the Ranau district and consists of 25 Class 2 and Class 3 rapids. Overall you can consider the river to be a Grade 3 experience with small waves and drops. The river ride also allows one to be closer to nature.</waterRafting_p6>
	<waterRafting_title4>Kiulu White Water Rafting</waterRafting_title4>
	<waterRafting_p7>Duration: 1 day trip </waterRafting_p7>
	<waterRafting_p8>The Kiulu River is the most suitable river for corporate groups, families with children and anyone whom has never experienced white water rafting. The easiest river to access also means that the trip is not a full day affair leaving you with much of your afternoon free. A Grade 2 level also means you really only need to know basic paddling skills. </waterRafting_p8>
	
	
	
    
	
 
 </waterRafting>
