<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<waterSport>
     <waterSport_title1>Borneo Water Entertainment</waterSport_title1>
     <waterSport_p1_1>The range of water sports available in</waterSport_p1_1>
	 <waterSport_p1_2>and in particular Sabah is vast and varied. For the avid diver Sabah is home to some of the best diving in the world. Islands like Layang-layang or </waterSport_p1_2>
	 <waterSport_p1_3>have a reputation that needs no explanation. Sailing is an wonderful in the region, with so many untouched islands there is plenty to explore, and if you want a personalised holiday what better way than to hire a beautiful traditional yacht and plan a charter that can cater to you requirements, including activities such as diving, trekking, exploring, snorkeling, in between activities relax onboard in beautiful surroundings and with excellent service.</waterSport_p1_3>
 
	<waterSport_title2>River Rafting</waterSport_title2>
	<waterSport_p2_1>is great fun and a brilliant day out, with runs for all levels and in stunning surroundings this is a great way to spend a day or so.</waterSport_p2_1>
	<waterSport_p2_2>include kayaking, dingy sailing, snorkeling, seabed walking, kite surfing, wind surfing, water skiing and wake boarding.</waterSport_p2_2>

	<waterSport_title3>Water Sports In Borneo</waterSport_title3>
	<waterSport_title3_sub1>Parasailing:</waterSport_title3_sub1>
	<waterSport_p3_1>Parasailing is a recreational activity where a person is towed behind a boat while attached to a specially designed parachute, known as a parasail.</waterSport_p3_1>
	<waterSport_p3_img1>~/images/parasailing.jpg</waterSport_p3_img1>
	
	<waterSport_title4>Banana Boat</waterSport_title4>
	<waterSport_p4>The whole family can ride the waves on our range of banana boat rides seating between 4 and 8 people at a time. Simply tell our Captain how fast you want to go.</waterSport_p4>
	<waterSport_p4_img1>~/images/bananaboat2.jpg</waterSport_p4_img1>
	
	<waterSport_title5>Sailing (Pico/Laser/Fun Boat/Hobie Cat)</waterSport_title5>
	<waterSport_p5>The Laser Pico dinghy is a small sailboat designed by Jo Richards in the mid-1990s and used primarily for training and day sailing. It can be crewed by one or two children or an adult. Current models come equipped with both a mainsail and a jib, but the jib is so small that it is faster sailed single handed using only the mainsail.</waterSport_p5>
	<waterSport_p5_img1>~/images/funboat.jpg</waterSport_p5_img1>
	
	
	<waterSport_title6>Sea Kayaking</waterSport_title6>
	<waterSport_p6>A Sea kayak or touring kayak is a kayak developed for the sport of paddling on open waters of lakes, bays, and the ocean. Sea kayaks are seaworthysmall boats with a covered deck and the ability to incorporate a spraydeck. They trade off the maneuverability of whitewater kayaks for cargo capacity, ease of straight-line paddling, and comfort for long journeys.</waterSport_p6>
	<waterSport_p6_img1>~/images/seakayaking.jpg</waterSport_p6_img1>
	
	<waterSport_title7>Advance Water Sport</waterSport_title7>
	<waterSport_title7_sub1>JetSki</waterSport_title7_sub1>
	<waterSport_p7>Cruising through the water on a jetski is great fun for both teenagers and adults. The sport is easy to learn.</waterSport_p7>
	<waterSport_p7_img1>~/images/jetski3.jpg</waterSport_p7_img1>
	
	<waterSport_title8>Water Ski</waterSport_title8>
	<waterSport_p8>Waterskiing is a sport where an individual is pulled behind a boat, skimming the surface.</waterSport_p8>
	<waterSport_p8_img1>~/images/Yuri_Arcurs_waterskiing4.jpg</waterSport_p8_img1>
	
	<waterSport_title9>WakeBoarding</waterSport_title9>
	<waterSport_p9>Wakeboarding is a surface  sport which involves riding a wakeboard over the surface of a body of water.</waterSport_p9>
	<waterSport_p9_img1>~/images/wakeboarding.jpg</waterSport_p9_img1>
	
	<waterSport_title10>Fly Fish</waterSport_title10>
	<waterSport_p10>The ultimate in speed and exhilaration. Two people sit either side of the fish and hold on tight as the aerodynamics of the beast allow it to 'fly' as it gathers speed behind the boat.</waterSport_p10>
	<waterSport_p10_img1>~/images/fly fish-thumb-150x100-6.jpg</waterSport_p10_img1>
	
	
	<waterSport_title11>Ultimate Water Sport</waterSport_title11>
	<waterSport_title11_sub1>Kitesurfing &amp; Kiteboarding</waterSport_title11_sub1>
	<waterSport_p11>is a surface water sport that uses the wind to pull a rider through the water on a small surfboard or a kiteboard (similar to a wakeboard). The terms kiteboarding and kitesurfing are interchangeable. There are a number of different styles of kiteboarding, including freestyle (most common and utilises standard kite and board) or wake-style (flatter water using board with bindings) and wave-riding which is focused on big waves using a board designed for wave riding.</waterSport_p11>
	<waterSport_p11_img1>~/images/kitesurfing.jpg</waterSport_p11_img1>
	
	<waterSport_title12>Wind Surfing</waterSport_title12>
	<waterSport_p12>A surface water sport that combines elements of surfing and sailing. It consists of a board usually two to four meters long, powered by the orthogonal effect of the wind on a sail. The rig is connected to the board by a free-rotating universal joint and comprises a mast, wishbone boom and sail. The sail area ranges from less than 3.0 m² to more than 12 m² depending on the conditions, the skill of the sailor and the type of windsurfing being undertaken. 	</waterSport_p12>
	<waterSport_p12_img1>~/images/windsurfing.jpg</waterSport_p12_img1>
	
	
	<waterSport_title13>Sky Diving</waterSport_title13>
	<waterSport_p13>is the action sport of exiting an aircraft and returning to Earth with the aid of gravity, then slowing down during the last part of the descent by using a parachute. It may or may not involve a certain amount of free-fall, a time during which the parachute has not been deployed and the body gradually accelerates to terminal velocity. New in Sabah- Malaysian Borneo. Sky Dive Sabah Drop Zone is located in the capital city : Kota Kinabalu. It is the only drop zone in this exotic, nature-adventure South East Asia location. We offer, static course, AFF, Tandem and fun jumps on weekends and are the local liaison for Exotic Sky Adventures</waterSport_p13>
	<waterSport_p13_img1>~/images/TMRound2.jpg</waterSport_p13_img1>
	
 </waterSport>
