<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mountKK>
   <mountKK_title>Welcome To Mount Kinabalu</mountKK_title>
   <mounKK_1stPic>~/images/mtk.jpg</mounKK_1stPic>
   <mounKK_1st_para>Mount Kinabalu rising to 4,101 metres, is the highest peak in Southeast Asia. Challenge yourself and attempt the summit of Borneo in Malaysia's first World Heritage Site, a reserve covering 754 km2. The climb takes you through varying vegetation zones offering breathtaking scenery and the chance to see some endemic plants including the rafflesia - the largest flower in the world, the Nepenthes Rajah - the world's largest pitcher plant, and more than 1,000 species of orchid.</mounKK_1st_para>
   <mounKK_2nd_para>Overnight in the the comfortable high altitude Laban Rata accommodation zone. The next day's early morning summit ascent starts at 3 am, so you will have to be up by 2 am in the morning! You should reach the summit plateau for the sunrise. If you are lucky enough to have a clear morning sky, the views of Sabah from the summit are unforgettable and manna from heaven for photographers. Grannies can do it so, although there may be moments of pain, you can too.</mounKK_2nd_para>
   <mounKK_2ndPic>~/images/15.jpg</mounKK_2ndPic>
   <mounKK_1st_sub_title>Via Ferrata Walk The Torq | Low's Peak Circuit</mounKK_1st_sub_title>
   <mounKK_3rd_para>An introduction to the world of Via Ferrata - a permanent network of iron rungs, rails and cables attached to the rock. Suitable for beginners, this activity takes you on the world's highest Via Ferrata and across a 6m Monkey Bridge. You will also attempt a 430m rock traverse and ascend. This activity is carried out on your descent from Low's Peak. The Via Ferrata detour will allow you to see stunning views and explore places off the beaten track.	Best suited for those with an above average level of fitness, the program not only includes the 6m Monkey bridge and 430m rock traverse but also a 763m long Via Ferrata.</mounKK_3rd_para>
	<mounKK_4th_para>An introduction to the world of Via Ferrata - a permanent network of iron rungs, rails and cables attached to the rock. Suitable for beginners, this activity takes you on the world's highest Via Ferrata and across a 6m Monkey Bridge. You will also attempt a 430m rock traverse and ascend. This activity is carried out on your descent from Low's Peak. The Via Ferrata detour will allow you to see stunning views and explore places off the beaten track.	Best suited for those with an above average level of fitness, the program not only includes the 6m Monkey bridge and 430m rock traverse but also a 763m long Via Ferrata.</mounKK_4th_para>
</mountKK>
